FRANKIE DICK

Software Developer

- Bristol, England
- **** 07734387436
- ☑ frankiedick.dev@gmail.com
- github.com/FrankieD96

Right to work

Core Skills

- React.js PHP

Education

iO Academy (07/2023 - 10/2023)

HTML and CSS, TailwindCSS, Git and Github, Vanilla JavaScript, React.js, OOP,

Open University (03/2021 - present)

time along-side working full-time to further my knowledge in software

Kingston University (09/2015 - 06/2018)

The Sixth form College Farnborough (09/2012 - 07/2014)

Interests

Summary

After 8 years as a senior technician at Apple, I transitioned into tech recruitment, acquiring deep insights into the tech landscape.

Now, I'm diving into software development at iO Academy, learning and working with technologies like HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, PHP, MySQL, PHPUnit. I've also learned OOP and TDD and I have used this as well as the other tech mentioned in solo and team projects using agile methodologies.

My ongoing, part-time degree in Computer Science, paired with my diverse background, positions me uniquely as I evolve into a dedicated software developer.

I love working in a team and connecting with people and I like to bring a positive, upbeat attitude to the workplace.

Projects

React App

Tech stack: React.js, html, CSS, git, agile

Communal bookshelf web platform built in a dev team of 5. This project was built using React for the frontend while seamlessly integrating with a prebuilt backend API. The platform offers features such as book claims, returns, reviews, and inventory management. We utilised Git for efficient version control and agile methodologies to guide our development process. Each feature or 'user story' was meticulously reviewed by peers and then by our trainer, ensuring both quality and alignment with the project's goals.

Bookswap API

Tech Stack: PHP, Laravel, MySQL, Postman, PHPUnit, git, agile

In a dev team of 5, we used Laravel to build a backend API for the React.js frontend that our team built in our previous project, which is detailed above. We used a TDD approach for this project, using PHPUnit to write integration tests. We were given documentation that we had to make sure our API matched up to so that it would work properly with the frontend. This required correctly returning the necessary information for specified endpoints.

Collection App

Tech Stack: PHP, MySQL, git, agile, html, CSS

I am currently working on a solo project to further hone my general PHP and database skills. I am building a simple collection site to display and interact with a collection of football shirts. I'll continue to add more features to this in my spare time.

Portfolio Website

Tech stack: html, CSS, JavaScript

Demonstrates my competence in web technologies such as HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, with a specific focus on fetching JSON data to ensure dynamic content and easy updates. Employing Git for version control, I have maintained a rigorous tracking of the project's evolution.

Work experience

2022-07 - 2023-04 Specialist Technology Recruitment Consultant

ADLIB, Bristol

Worked across a range of specialist disciplines including Development/Engineering, QA/Testing, DevOps, Infrastructure, CTOs / Tech Leaders and much more. Specialised in supporting Software Houses, Tech Consultancies, Household Brands, start-ups and scaleups, B Corps, Tech4Goods and GreenTech / Sustainability specialists. Gained a useful insight into the tech market from a recruitment perspective.

2014-09 - 2022-07 Technical Expert

Apple

Responsibilities included mentoring and training the team, resolving customer issues, repairing iPhones, doing appointments at the Genius Bar for all Apple devices and being one of the iOS experts in the store. I achieved consistently good results both personally and as part of the team. Guided other technicians with their knowledge and lead them to hit targets set out by the company. This role also included a lot of operational planning as we dealt with a large number of serialised repair parts and products aswell as some scheduling.

2019-06 - 2019-11 Assistant Producer (Internship)

Apple

Learned the new technologies necessary to be an impactful member of the team. Responsibilities included; planning shows, cleaning tracks, editing and building promo's. I worked as a producer on various live streamed shows (including Artist led shows: Jax Jones, Krept & Konan)